David Ian Mason

{Full-Stack Software Engineer}

About me

I am a former pharmaceutical scientist turned software developer with a strong background in problem-solving, decision-making, teamwork, leadership and communication as well as a good understanding of the importance in documentation. I began this transition after completely falling for the constant learning and fast development of programming and as such I am looking forward to joining a team where I can use my dedication towards continuously improving myself, those around me and the code before me.

School of Code

Full-Stack Developer | Sep 2023 - Present

- Chosen from over 3000 applicants to complete an intense 16-week, full-stack development bootcamp.
- Developed full-stack JS apps using a number of tools such as React and PostgreSQL.
- Weekly hackathons putting newly taught concepts into practice.
- Pair and team programming daily during workshops, hackathons and projects.
- Active participation in the Design steps of apps through ideation, user research, creation of user personas as well as low & high fidelity wire-framing.
- Use of Agile methodology during teamwork focusing on early MVP development and iterative improvements.
- Helped other Bootcampers to understand new topics when they were struggling.
- Assisted other groups during the final projects to fix issues.

SoC Project - BrumAI Website

Brief: Our client, BrumAI, required a new modern website which would better display their community as well as be easy to manage.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, JSX, React, Next.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, SupaBase, MUI, AntDesign, Netlify.

Time Frame: 4-weeks. Team Size: 6.

Focuses:

User Experience:

- $\,$ Next.JS v14 was chosen due to its Server-Side Rendering to increase the speed of the website and improve SEO.
- The website was designed based on user journeys to ensure information most wanted by users was displayed first.
 - Responsiveness for all screen sizes.

Ease of Management:

- SupaBase used for the database due to its UI interface requiring no prior SQL knowledge.
- Information likely to change is stored in a single data file and imported so no need to search through code to update.
 - Documents created to explain how to manage the website.

Contributions:

- Data sorting functionality based on date of event.
- Light/Dark mode functionality.
- Lead bug-fixing when a problem occurred.

Contact

- David_Mason_@hotmail.co.uk
- **Q** 07914 637 286
- linkedin.com/in/davidianmason1702
- o github.com/DayHikari
- **№** Bedford, UK

Skills

Front-End:

| JavaScript | React | Next.js | | TypeScript | HTML | CSS |

Back-End:

| PostegreSQL | Rest API | | Express.js | Node.js |

Testing:

| Playwright | Vitest | Supertest | | Jest | React Testing Library |

Personal Projects

Portfolio &

My personal portfolio developed using Next.JS and Tailwind.CSS.

100 Day Code Blog &

Solo project to practice Database and MVC Rest API usage.

Weather App 🤌

Solo project to practice the use of APIs, DOM manipulation through user interactions and conditional rendering.

Rating Component &

Pair project using Frontend Mentor to practice HTML and CSS as well as DOM manipulation.

Calculator &

Solo project to practice conditional logic and DOM manipulation.

SoC Project - Memory Echo &

Problem: School of Code bootcampers are faced with an intense course with many different topics taught on a daily basis. As such, it can be difficult to record and then revise all the topics.

Solution: Memory Echo, a spaced-repetition app designed to record topics and remind bootcampers when to revise the topics.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.JS, REST API, Express.js, PostgreSQL.

Time Frame: 1 week. Team Size: 6.

MVP Achieved:

- Deployed with connection between front and back end.
- Mobile-first design.
- Allow users to add new topics which are stored in a PostgreSQL database.
- Topics stored in the database fetched and displayed in the front end.
- Function to highlight topics to be revised based on date added using space repetition practices.

Experience

Achilles Therapeutics Ltd

Senior GMP Production Scientist | 2021 - 2023 GMP Production Scientist | 2020 - 2021

- Led a team of ten within the lab during manufacturing.
- Managed scheduling and personnel.
- Line managed two junior team members.
- Wrote documentation for processes and events.
- Completed projects to a high standard and tight deadlines.
- Worked on and led projects encompassing multiple departments.
- Communicated with stakeholders regarding projects.
- Helped with the continuous development of the manufacturing process.

Lonza

Biotechnologist 2 | 2019 - 2020 Biotechnologist 1 | 2018 - 2019

- Worked in varying teams daily.
- Managed projects.
- Led teams within the lab during manufacturing.
- Trained new members on the process.
- Problem-solving when an incident occurred.

Tesco

Cashier (Part-time) | 2017 - 2018

Kinkowan Senior High School, Japan

Assistant Language Teacher | 2015 - 2017

The Binding Site Company

Laboratory Technician | 2013 - 2014

Methodologies

| Agile | TDD | | Disney Ideation |

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Communication
- Quick learner
- Problem-solving
- Organised
- Adaptability
- Leadership
- Decision-making
- Self driven
- Documentation

Personal

- Outside of coding, I enjoy playing Grand-Strategy and City-Building games which require planning and foresight.
- I also enjoy reading and listening to books. I recently started reading 'The Wheel of Time' by Robert Jordan which I am enjoying.
- I have been teaching myself to play the violin which has been difficult but I am making (slow) progress so should start sounding passable soon!
- I am also studying Korean and Japanese and love visiting both countries!

Education

BSc (Hons) Biochemistry Sheffield Hallam University | 2011 - 2015 1st-Class Degree